Guide to the Douglas C. Engelbart Papers M0638
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Accession 1998-094
  - Engelbart Notes, 1960-1988
    - DCE Notes Binders, 1969-1971
      - Planning References, 1969-1970 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - Notes for BC Story, 1969-1970 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Other Text Manipulation System, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - DCE Archives, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - NIC Working Papers, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - DCE Notebooks, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - DCE Notes Binders, 1973-1985
      - Planning & Presentation, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Programming References, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Programming Tools & References, 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - E Notes, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - E Draft Docs, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Application Development Group, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - UDEV Notes, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 3P, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - E, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - O-P Notes Planning, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Bootstrap Community Notes, Old, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Bootstrap Project, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Prop Notes, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - DCE Notes Binders re: FRAMAC, Bootstrap Community, 1971-1972
      - ARC RFP Draft (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - NLS Utility, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Thinkpiece Drafts, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Working Notes, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - FRAME work, Bootstrap Community, NP (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - FRAMAC, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - FRAMAC Tape Transcriptions, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Bootstrap Community, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - DCE Notes & RDP Diskettes, 1981-1988
      - Misc. Correspondence, Notes, Etc., 1988-1989 (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - Touchstone Issues (Box 31, Folder 67)
      - Augment, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Bootstrap Forum, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - CAD/CAM/CALS Initiative, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - CADoc Report, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - CSCW, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - DEC Tech Eval, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Department Resource Processors, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - EMMS & Apple, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - HP Labs, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Hypertext Workshop, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - ISO/IEC Proposal, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - MDC, NASP, DEC, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - MOA reqs & specs, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Rand Meeting, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - Stars, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Navy CAD/CAM, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Org Aug & H-Doc, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - Port, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - SU Email, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - Teleforum, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - Indexing, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - NLS File system, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Augment, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - Document System Prep, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - Eval/AI Tools, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 26)
      - Hypertext Conference, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 27)
      - IBM Delivery System, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 28)
      - Implementation Workshop, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 29)
      - Navy CAD/CAM, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 30)
      - RINS, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 31)
      - 5" Computer Disks (approx. 40), 1987 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - DCE McDonnell Douglas Desk Files, 1977-1989
      - Augment Mail (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - Absence Reports, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 26)
      - Phone Lists, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 27)
      - Bootstrapping, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 28)
      - Richer, Mark, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 29)
      - Dunham, Robert (Box 33, Folder 30)
      - Business Isuues, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 31)
      - Andrews, Don, 1985-1986 (Box 33, Folder 32)
      - Bellville, Robert, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 33)
      - DCE, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 34)
      - ASD (Box 33, Folder 35)
      - MDC Project Memos, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 36)
      - Augment (Box 33, Folder 37)
      - RING Grist (Box 33, Folder 38)
      - MDC NP (Box 33, Folder 39)
      - SRI Business (Box 33, Folder 40)
      - MDC Productivity (Box 33, Folder 41)
      - Voter, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 42)
      - Weller Doc & Manuals (Box 33, Folder 43)
      - Plan Notes, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 44)
      - Watson (Box 33, Folder 45)
      - ARC Description (Box 33, Folder 46)
      - Workshop (Box 33, Folder 47)
      - ISD Meeting Records (Box 33, Folder 48)
      - Straus, Don, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 49)
      - Evans, Dave (Box 33, Folder 50)
      - Babbie, Earl (Box 33, Folder 51)
      - Schill, John (Box 33, Folder 52)
      - Voter (Box 33, Folder 53)
      - Peak Perfomance (Box 33, Folder 54)
      - ISG (Box 33, Folder 55)
      - CP-ARC, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 56)
    - DCE Data Cards, Optical Mouse, Etc., 1982
      - Xerox Experimental Optical Mouse (gift to DCE), 1982 (Box 27, Folder 54)
      - Data Processing Cards with Note4s, References, Etc. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - DCE Notes, 1960's (?) Files, 1965-1981
      - ELITE, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 37)
      - EPRI, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 38)
      - Tymshare 10-K, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 39)
      - Jordan, Dale, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 40)
      - Retrieve, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 41)
      - BID, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 42)
      - Presentation Materials, 1978-1980 (Box 44, Folder 43)
      - Misc. Correspondence, 1965-1973 (Box 44, Folder 44)
      - ASIS, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 45)
      - Bonneville RFP, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 46)
      - Bootstrap Project, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 47)
      - SWEDCO, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 48)
      - Herman Miller, Inc., 1969 (Box 44, Folder 49)
      - NAS, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 50)
      - Electronics Magazine, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Microfilm (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Ojai Notes (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - USAF Automation Requirement for ADAM, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Michel (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Meetings & Conferences NP, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - UCLA Talk, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Wasserman (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Diebold (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - NDN on Management (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - NCC, UK (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Misc. Contacts (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - NSF Contacts (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - IFIP Graphics Methodology Conference, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - DCE Publications, 1961-1969 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Intelligence (Reports, Journals, Etc.), 1973-1987
    - Intelligence Collection 1973-1976
      - Misc. Publications, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Misc. Publications, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Intelligence Collection 1976-1978
      - Misc. Publications, 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Misc. Publications, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Intelligence Collection 1979-1983
      - Misc. Publications, 1979-1983 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Intelligence Collection 1983-1987
      - Misc. Publications, 1983-1987 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Manuals, Guides, Other Publications
    - User Guides
      - Misc. User Guides - IBM, HP, etc. (Box 23, Folder 49)
      - SF THW Brochures (Box 23, Folder 50)
      - SF THW Brochures (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - TOPS-20 Reference Manuals Vol.1-5 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - DECnet & Network User Guides, 1982-1983
      - Misc. Guides & Manuals, 1982-1983 (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - TOPS-20 User Guides, 1982-1983 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - Tymnet (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Augment (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Zipload (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Help Data Bases Vol.4 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - AH-Encrypta (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Manuals, 1978-1986
      - Z-100 Manual, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - PC/Forth Manual, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - Netwroks & Communications Buyers Guide, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - TOPS-20 Manuals, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Tymvalidate Manuals (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - Bliss Pocket Guide (Box 45, Folder 21)
      - DIGITAL Networking Pocket Guide (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - RMS-20 Manual (Box 45, Folder 23)
      - DIL Manual (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - EDT-20 Manuals (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - Augment Output Processes Beginner's Guide, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Misc. Manuals, 1978-1980 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - TOPS-20 Files: Macros, Monitor Calls, Monitor Tables, Etc., 1979-1988
      - DBS-20 BSYS, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - TOPS-20 JSYS (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Ontyme PROFS, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - TOPS-20 Manuals (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - TOPS-20 Macro (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - TOPS-20 Usage System (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - 20X Monitor Tables (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - TOPS-20 Reference Manuals, IBM Basic, AUGUST System Manual, Etc., 1969-1987
      - TOPS-20 Dumper, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - August System Admin Guide, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - IBM Basic Guide (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Pdp/o Reference Handbook, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - 4 - Command Meta Language, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - DECNET-20 Phase IV (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - TOPS-20 Monitor Calls Reference (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - TOPS-20 Command Reference Manual (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Misc. Publications, DCE & Others, 1960-1981
      - #1 Special Considerations..., 1960 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - #2 Augmented Human Intellect (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - #3 Conceptual Framework..., 1963 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - #5 A Research Center..., 1968 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Intellectual Implications..., 1970 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - #8 Design Considerations... (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Line Processor... (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - #14 Software Engineering Environment, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - #16 Toward Integrated, Evolutionary..., 1978 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - #17 Evolving the Organization..., 1981 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - #20 Authorship Provisions..., 1981 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - #21 The Augmented Knowledge Workshop (AKW), 1986 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - SRI-ARC Reports, 1960-1975 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Misc. Publications, DCE & Others, 1968-1982
      - Command Meta Language System, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Experimental Grpahic User's Guide, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Games That Teach the Fundamentals... (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Coordinated Information Services (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Display Techniques... (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - The Augmented Knowledge Workshop, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Executive Information Tools (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Use Of Computers... in the U.S. Senate, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Computer Augmentation of the Human Knowledge qworkshop, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Office Automation..., 1980 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Computer as Communication Device, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Innovation, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Raylene Pak (Bootstrap Development Manager) Files, 1976-1990
    - Raylene Pak Files 1978-1990
      - DEC-ATF Proposal (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Compilers, Switchable (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - TAC (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Augment Service in Support of AFCC, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Tymshare Administration Training (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - System XXVI Site Inspection Guide, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - CECOM, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - LIF Message Forwarding, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Output Processor (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - KCC User Documentation (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Servio Sales Package (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Misc. Articles, Printouts, Correspondence, Disks (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Augment Technical Memorandum- Regulation Search Design, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Elite User Guide (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Augment Technical Memorandum - Terminal Line Protocol, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Digital Proposal, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - MSL Camera (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Input Processor (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - ECO Meetings, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Raylene Pak Files 1976-1981
      - Old Project Update Information, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Old Bootstrap for Historians (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Debugger, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - FE #1, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - NLS10 Subsys V.2, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Debugger Programmer's Guide, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Experimental Graphics User Guide, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - DAD User Guide, 1977 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - On-Line Programmers Management System Guides, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Design & Implementation of a Multi-Process Debugger, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - CLI Implementation Memorandum, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - CML, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - NLS9 Builder's Guide, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Tree Meta Report (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Library Subsystem (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - DAD LDR Utility (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Raylene Pak Files 1979-1986
      - Tymshare CompSrc, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 31)
      - Tymshare Debugging, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 32)
      - Tymshare BSYS, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 33)
      - Tymshare Tenex User Documentation, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 34)
      - CML Design, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 35)
      - TOPS-20 Manuals, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 36)
      - Telecopy, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 37)
      - Reminders Test, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 38)
      - OnTyme (Box 50, Folder 39)
      - Search, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 40)
      - Suspense (Box 50, Folder 41)
      - Tynment Aux Circuits, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 42)
      - New Calendar (Box 50, Folder 43)
      - Ident (Box 50, Folder 44)
      - Signatures (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Seg-to-Aug (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - JMSearch (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Calendar (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Reminders, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Talus, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Outside Docs, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Strawman Architecture, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - DAD Debugger Files, 1978-1979 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Raylene Pak Files 1977-1990
      - Old Port (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - McAir Port Study, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Port, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Team 1 Ethernet, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Conference (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Mailer, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Spares (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Touchstone Maintenance (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - OHS Implementation Plan (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Xanadu, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - AH Systems, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Output Processor User Guide, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Command Meta Language, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Bootstrap Institute Launch, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Journal Patching (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Frontend, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - EXEC Version 7 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Publication Orders (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - To-Dos, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Journal, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Multislot Timer (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - 12246 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Tymnet Charges (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Augment/Ontym Working Group, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Augment Misc. Goals (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - System Build Processing, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - FTPC (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Command Sequences, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - ADRMNP & PSEDT Binders
    - FESRC CLI (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 4- Command Meta Language (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 6- Frontend; 7- CLI; 8- Subsystems (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 9- Processor; 10- Line Processor; 11- Conversion (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - FE System Guides (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - BE System Guides (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - PSEDT (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - ADRMNT (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Tenex Guide (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - SS SRC Programs (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - ARPANET, 1971-1974
    - ARPA Network User Guide, 1971 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Current Catalog, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Current Catalog, 1972-1973 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Current Directory, 1973 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Network Resource Notebook, 1973 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Current Network Protocols (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - DCE Photograph Portrait, 1969 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - CML & NLS Binders
    - Tymshare Documentation 1-2-3 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Tymshare Documentation 4 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Tymshare Documentation 5 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Tymshare Documentation 6-7-8 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Tymshare Documentation 9-10-11 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - G-DOC Memoranda, 1963-1964 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Front End System Binders, 1976-1983
    - Program Printouts, 1976-1979 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - ARC Loader, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Locator vol.1-3, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Appendices (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Hash (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Frontend Documentation (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - NLS (oNLine System) Binders, 1976-1979
    - Monitor Calls Manual (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - FE #1/2, 1979 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - NLS BE #1-3 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - PDP10 & DEC10 Binders, 1981
    - PDP10 System Reference Manual (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Subsystems (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - DEC-10 User Guide (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - TUTOR, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tymshare Mail (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Library to User Options Subsystems (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Program Printouts: Jumper, Jentry, SIG Object Code, SMTP, FMover, Conference, 1985-1989
    - BESRC (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - JDUMPER, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - LCAO Listings, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - IDSLAVE, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - JENTRY, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - SIG Object Code, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - SMTP (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - FMOVER, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Conference (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Augment Command Sequences, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Program Printouts, Digital Order Brochures, Etc., 1976-1991
    - Systems Concepts, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - FIG43 Office Computer Tape, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - TOPS-20 Monitor Calls User Guide (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Program Printouts, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - SRI-ARC Experimental Graphics User Guide, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Catalogs, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Misc. Program Printouts (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Tymshare Terminal Photograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SRI, 1976
    - NLS Programmer's Guide, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 66)
    - Command Meta Language, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 67)
    - Experimental Graphics User Guide, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 68)
    - Misc. Reports, Articles, 1972-1977 (Box 39, Folder 69)
    - Abstracts, Memoranda, 1963-1964 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - CWS Paper, 1963-1964 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Misc. Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Memoranda, Notes, Reports, 1960-1974 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - CSCW, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Toward Integrated Evolutionary Office Systems, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - ELITE, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - User Interface Design Issues, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - XDOC 1974; ARPANET 1975, 1974-1975
    - Remote Procedure Call References, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - NLS X-Progs, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - XDOC Catalog, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - ACOTCO 25350, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - SRI National Technical Information Center, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Our Writings, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Misc.
    - Journals, 1958-1986 (Box 1A (1998-094))
    - Yearly Calendars (notated), 1967-1970 (Box 1B (1998-094))
    - Audiocassettes: Meetings (5/20/82, 6/11/82), Health Considerations Related to VDT Use (1982), The Interface to Human – Computer Productivity, The Concept of VDT Usability, Keynote Panel (Box 1B (1998-094))
    - computer tapes (Box 104b (1998-094))
- Series 3. Media
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains computer as well as audiovisual materials from various accessions.
  - Subseries 3.1. Demonstrations
    - A technical session presentation at the Fall Joint Computer Conference in San Francisco: a demonstration of the "Mouse", with Douglas Engelbart. Copyright, Douglas Engelbart.[VHS copies -Accession 1986-030], 1968-12-08; 1988-013 / 1999-032; 3 videocassettes (VHS): use copy (Box 3, Object 1-3)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      This content has been digitized: M0638_s3_b03_01 - M0638_s3_b03_03
    - SRI Kine #2 Reels 1-3, 1969-10-14; 3 film(s) (Box 1 (1988-013), Object 1-3)
      M0638_b01_01 - M0638_s3_b03_03
    - Augmentation Systems and Information Science (ASIS) SRI Kine Computer Film ASIS 69 #2, 1969-10-1; 4 film(s) (Box 1 (1988-013), Object 4-7)
      A Presentation at the 32nd Annual Meeting of the American Society for Information Science, San Francisco October 1, 1969. A Demonstration of the "Mouse" by Douglas Engelbart and staff, Augmented Human Intellect Research Center. Copyright Douglas Engelbart.
      M0638_b01_04 - M0638_b01_07
    - Technical Session Presentation, Fall Joint Computer Conference - Demonstration of the Mouse, 1968-12-08 (Box 2 (1988-013), Object 1-3)
      M0638_b02_01 - M0638_s3_b02_03
    - Mouse Demo VHS copies (9 tapes), 1968-12-08 (Box 3 (1988-013))
    - Mouse Demo Beta copies (9 tapes), 1968-12-08 (Box 4 (1988-013))
  - Subseries 3.2. Accession 1998-094 Audiovisual Media & Machines
    - Films: ASIS 69 Reels 1-3 (copy 1 and copy 8), 1969 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Films: FJCC '68 Reels 1-3 (Print 5) (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - SEM-2 and SEM-4 audio & videocassettes (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - SEM-5 Masters U-Matic Videocassettes, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - SEM-5 Masters U-Matic Videocassettes, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Voting Wands (approx. 16) (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Various machines, prototypes, and parts; including voting machine parts, modems, keysets, etc. (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3.3. Accession 2002-113 (Award Ceremony videos & DVD-R copies)
    - The Webby's Lifetime Achievement Award Douglas Engelbart [VHS; DVD copy], 2001 (Box 1 (2002-113), Object 1)
    - The Webby's: Douglas Engelbart Interview [VHS; DVD copy], 2001-07-11 (Box 1 (2002-113), Object 2)
    - The 2000 National Science and Technology Medals and Laureate Video [VHS 17:13; DVD copy], 2000-12-01 (Box 1 (2002-113), Object 3)
    - The 2000 National Science and Technology Medals and Laureate Video [VHS 38:13; DVD copy], 2000-12-01 (Box 1 (2002-113), Object 4)
    - 2000 Induction Ceremony National Inventors Hall of Fame [VHS 90:00; DVD copy] (Box 1 (2002-113), Object 5)
    - The Franklin Institute Awards Ceremony and Gala [VHS 01:17:00; DVD copy], 1999-04-29 (Box 1 (2002-113), Object 6)
    - Computer Museum History Center 2001 Fellows Awards: Highlights [VHS 40:00; DVD copy], 2001-11-02 (Box 1 (2002-113), Object 7)
  - Subseries 3.4. Accession 2007-323, 10 box(es)
    - System tapes (Box 1-8 (2007-323))
    - System tapes (Box 9 (2007-323))
    - VHS Tapes (6): Engelbart Seminar (pt. 2-4): SRI International Poulter Video; The Transcendental Meditation Program; Margaret Consultant 9/28/93 (Box 9 (2007-323))
    - VHS Tapes (6): Doug at MITRE, 8/31/2005; Provocation ’98; The Lens Project Video; Engelbart’s Unfinished Revolution; New Paradigms for Using Computers, 7/27/1995; Cal Pava Fund. (Box 10 (2007-323))
  - Subseries 3.5 Miscellaneous film & video
    - "Tasker- Only Scenes. First Try, Off In Exposure and Aim. Used anyway for SF-ACM 18 Apr 73 - DCE" 16mm Silent -- Not Good (Box 1 (misc), Object 1)
    - [unlabeled; EBR 4/14/1969 Scene 1 Take 1 slate on film] (Box 1 (misc), Object 2)
    - [unlabeled; arrived in envelope] (Box 1 (misc), Object 3)
    - [unlabeled 1998-094 16mm film, cleaned by Monaco 12/2002] (Box 1 (misc), Object 4)
    - Eidophon Out Reel 2 25:30 (Box 1 (misc), Object 5)
    - Backup For Seattle Presentation. NLS Demo. [U-matic in new housing, VHS copy, original tape housing], 1977-12 (Box 3 (misc), Object 1-3)
    - Stanford Research Institute/ Augmentation Research Center "Our Tape" Sony V-32 Reel & Betacam Dub, 1974-12-05 (Box 3 (misc), Object 4-5)
    - Engelbart Screen Footage, Original. Film Shot on 25-Apr-74. No Sound. Shows Text Being Manipulated On Screen (Box 3 (misc), Object 6)